https://typewell.com/privacy-policy/

844-897-3935
Web Linking server status:
Search for a topic or article...
FAQ
Legal Stuff
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Effective Date:
12/1/2014
TypeWell.com and its related services and products (“Website”) are owned and operated by Catalina Solutions, LLC, d/b/a TypeWell (“TypeWell”). TypeWell has adopted this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) to inform you that it collects personal information (“Personal Information”) when you use the Website and to explain how this Personal Information is used. TypeWell has also adopted this Privacy Policy because it respects your privacy and believes that it should clearly and transparently discloses its privacy practices to the user.
TypeWell respects your privacy and makes a concerted effort to protect your identity and personal information.
TYPEWELL MAY CHANGE, MODIFY, AMEND, SUSPEND, TERMINATE, OR REPLACE THIS PRIVACY POLICY FROM TIME TO TIME AND WITHIN ITS SOLE AND ABSOLUTE DISCRETION. IN THE EVENT TYPEWELL CHANGES, MODIFIES, AMENDS, OR REPLACES THIS PRIVACY POLICY, THE EFFECTIVE DATE, LOCATED ABOVE, WILL CHANGE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE WEBSITE AFTER A CHANGE IN THE EFFECTIVE DATE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY CONSTITUTES YOUR MANIFESTATION OF ASSENT TO THE CHANGE, MODIFICATION, AMENDMENT, OR REPLACEMENT CONTAINED WITHIN.
1. TypeWell may collect the following Personal Information from you:
Any information that you submit to the Website, Social Media or similar third-party sites or applications;
First and last name;
Email address;
Mailing address;
Date of birth;
Phone Number
Photograph/image;
Country;
Business name, business website, business email address;
Payment information;
Other required account or other information visible to the User as requested by the service.
Your IP address;
Your order history;
Your use of the Website;
Information stored in cookies, pixel tags, or web beacons;
Analytic data from Google Analytics;
Account holder and payment information; and
Any other additional analytic data that you voluntarily submit to the Website
TypeWell may collect this personal information from you through various channels, including, but not limited to, through your voluntary submission of information to the Website, through requests initiated by you through the Website, through TypeWell’s newsletter or survey, through communication with third parties such as banks, through the collection and analysis of information concerning your computer and browsing activities, through the use of cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, Google Analytics, and through other sources permitted by law.
TypeWell may collect this personal information from you through credit card payments processed by third party payment processors, such as PayPal. PayPal’s Privacy Policy can be found at https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full.
TypeWell uses Google Analytics to help analyze how users use the site. The tool uses "cookies," which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors' use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity for TypeWell.
2. TypeWell uses this Personal Information to:
Provide you with the Website, process any customer service or support requests made by you, process any orders or business contemplated by the Website, communicate with you, identify and fix problems with the Website, update you on changes to the Website, communicate with you concerning your account, to complete a transaction you initiated, and to update you on TypeWell’s services offered through the Website or the services of third parties.
TypeWell may share your Personal Information with third parties where it has obtained your consent, whether express or implied, with third party service providers to provide you with services initiated at your request, with TypeWell’s parents, subsidiaries, successors, and assigns, and with TypeWell’s business partners who offer services through or in association with the Website.
TypeWell may use your personal information, including your email address, to communicate with you about the Website, your use of services related to the Website such as promotions, advertising placements, and/or the purchase of goods or services. TypeWell may also use your Personal Information, including your email address, for marketing, research, and advertising purposes. TypeWell will allow you to opt out of email marketing. Each email sent contains a very easy and automated way for you to stop receiving email messages from us in the future. If you believe you have received unwanted, unsolicited email sent via this system or purporting to be sent via this system, please forward a copy of that email with your comments to support@typewell.com for review. We will look into the matter immediately.
TypeWell will never sell, share, or rent individual personal information with anyone without your advance written permission or unless ordered by a court of law. Information submitted to us is only available to employees managing this information for purposes of contacting you or sending you emails based on your request for information and to contracted service providers for purposes of providing services relating to our communications with you, including operating TypeWell’s Website and conducting TypeWell’s business.
Except as otherwise stated herein, TypeWell will not sell, transfer, or lease your Personal Information to any individual, business, or government entity except to: (1) respond to authorized information requests by government authorities; (2) to respond to a court order or subpoena; (3) to protect the employees, independent contractors, users, members, officers, directors, or shareholders of TypeWell; or (4) to help prevent against fraud or the violation of any applicable law, statute, regulation, ordinance, or treaty.
You are solely responsible for the protection of any Personal Information that you submit to the Website, and you are advised to review that Personal Information before you submit it to the Website.
This website uses Google Analytics to help analyze how you use the Website. The tool uses "cookies," which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors' use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity for TypeWell.
You acknowledge and agree that TypeWell is not responsible for any third party links, content, or communications sent to you from entities or individuals that TypeWell does not own or control. You are advised to review the privacy policies of third party websites.
Comply or attempt to comply with all laws domestic and foreign.
3. TypeWell stores your Personal Information in the following manner:
Your Personal Information is stored and processed on computers and servers in the United States and, through your use of the Website, you unequivocally consent to the processing and storage of your Personal Information. You understand and agree that TypeWell may continue to store your information after you cease use of the service or disable your Account.
TypeWell uses commercially reasonable efforts and standard technology to store and help prevent against the unauthorized disclosure of your personal or Personal Information. Though it undertakes commercially reasonable efforts to protect your Personal Information, no Website is completely safe. Accordingly, you provide all such personal or Personal Information at your own risk.
In order to protect your Personal Information, all supplied sensitive/credit information is encrypted into TypeWell’s gateway database, which is only accessible by individuals authorized with special access rights to such database, who are required to keep the Personal Information confidential. After a transaction, your Personal Information will not be stored on TypeWell’s servers.
4. TypeWell may share your Personal Information with third parties in the following circumstances:
Where TypeWell is complying or in good faith attempting to comply with any law, regulation or law enforcement request. Where TypeWell has obtained your consent, where sharing or disclosure of your personal or Personal Information is necessary to provide you with the Website and/or services associated therewith, where sharing or disclosure of your personal or Personal Information is necessary to share personal or Personal Information with TypeWell’s parents, subsidiaries, successors, assigns, licensees, affiliates, or business partners, where TypeWell has been purchased by a third party, where sharing or disclosure of your personal or Personal Information is necessary to respond to requests by government authorities, where your personal or Personal Information is demanded by a court order or subpoena, where sharing or disclosure of your personal or Personal Information is needed to protect the employees, independent contractors, officers, directors, members, users, or shareholders of TypeWell, and where sharing or disclosure of your personal or Personal Information is needed to help prevent against fraud or the violation of any applicable law, statute, regulation, ordinance, or treaty.
5. Purchase or sale of the Website or other assets:
TypeWell may purchase other businesses or sell components of its business, including, but not limited to, the Website. In the event TypeWell purchases another business or sells any component of its business, your Personal Information will continue to be used consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy.
6. You may stop TypeWell from collecting your Personal Information by:
Adjusting your web browser settings, limiting cookies or other tracking techniques, or by ceasing your use of the Website. You may contact TypeWell with any requests regarding your information, but TypeWell reserves the right to act or not act upon such requests.
7. When using the Website, you are obligated to:
Inform TypeWell of any changes to your Personal Information, and protect the security of your username, password, and Personal Information.
8. California Residents
California residents have the right to receive information that identifies any third party companies or individuals that TypeWell has shared your Pwithin Information with in the previous calendar year, as well as a description of the categories of Personal Information disclosed to that third party. You may obtain this information once a year and free of charge by contacting TypeWell at the address below.
9. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Policy
The Website is not intended for or directed to users under the age of 18, and TypeWell does not knowingly or intentionally collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13 or other minors. Where appropriate, TypeWell takes reasonable measures to determine that users are adults of legal age and to inform minors not to submit such information to the Website or in response to advertisements. If you are concerned that personal information may have been inadvertently provided to or collected by TypeWell, please contact us immediately so appropriate steps may be taken to remove such information from TypeWell’s database.
10. Contact and Notices
All questions and concerns regarding this Privacy Policy may be submitted to TypeWell, P.O. Box 221, Patagonia, AZ 85624; with a copy emailed to support@typewell.com.
Next Article in Topic
Copyright Policy
Previous Article in Topic
TypeWell Software End-User License Agreement (EULA)
Related Articles
Software Security & HIPAA Compliance
Terms of Use for TypeWell.com Website
Terms of Service for Continuing Education Website (LEO)
We run on re:amaze
